It seems today that all you see
Is violence in movies and sex on TV
But where are those good old-fashioned values
On which we used to rely?
Lucky there's a family guy
Lucky there's a man who positively can do
All the things that make us
Laugh and cry
He's... a... fam... ily... guy!
布莱恩的剧
Brian's Play
即兴爱人--Brian Griffin
哇哦 真为Brian感到兴奋
Wow, I'm so excited for Brian.
记住 孩子们 如果剧很糟糕,
Remember, kids-- if it's terrible,
我们最后就都说 "你做到了!"
at the end, we all say, "You did it!"
真不敢相信我们在去剧院的路上
I can't believe we're going to the theater
今天Chris刚把一只老鼠淹死在水坑里
the same day Chris drowned a mouse in a puddle.
我是说 我们不需要一天的时间来冷静一下吗?
I mean, don't we need a day to clear our heads?
啊 这让我想起了往事
Boy, this takes me back.
我曾经是 呃…
You know, I was, uh...
是高中时期话剧的一个演员
kind of one of those theater kids in high school.
突然Seymour...
Suddenly Seymour...
他净化了我
He purified me
他净化了你
He purified you
突然Seymour...
Suddenly Seymour...
安德鲁斯夫人 我又拉在花盆里了
Mrs. Andrews, I pooped in the pot again.
我需要人帮我清理一下
I'm gonna need somebody to clean me up.
这次真的很糟糕
It's really bad this time.
哇哦 这么多人
Wow, what a turnout.
哦 嗨 那是Glenn
Oh, hey, there's Glenn.
嗨 伙计们
Hey, guys.
嗨 这是我今晚的伴Consuela
Hey, this is my date, Consuela.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
好吧 我们只是朋友
Okay, we're here as friends,
不过总有一天我会让你改变主意的
but I'm gonna change your mind one day.
哦 真为Brian感到骄傲
Oh, I'm so proud of Brian.
很难想象他还是曾经那个
It's hard to believe he's the same dog
对着菠萝狂吠四小时的狗
who barked at a pineapple for four hours.
拉好你的钱包 我都看到你的卫生棉条了
Close your purse. I can see your tampons.
还有为什么你需要六个
And why do you need six?
你究竟经历了什么
What happens to you?
今晚的明星来了
There's the man of the hour.
嘿 Brian 你能想象吗
Hey, Brian, can you believe
我是在公路边上找到这件外套的
I found this blazer on the side of the highway?
谢谢你们能来
Hey, guys. Thanks for coming.
重要的夜晚 Brian 你感觉怎么样
Big night, Brian. How you feeling?
嗯 有点紧张
Well, a little nervous.
我就希望一切顺利
I just want it to go well.
祝我好运
Fingers crossed.
有中场休息吗
Will there be an intermission?
因为这会决定我是否
Because that will determine whether or not
带这个空Gatorade饮料瓶进去
I bring this empty Gatorade bottle into the theater.
这真是无法忍受
TOM: This is unacceptable!
抱歉 我得离开了
Sorry, guys, I got to go.
他们没在Tom Tucker的座位上粘遮蔽胶带
They didn't put masking tape over a seat for Tom Tucker
于是他就在那里发飙了
and he's in there pitching a fit.
你知道我是谁么
TOM: Do you know who I am?!
我是Tom Tucker 妈逼的
I'm Tom Tucker, damn it!
我一小时挣的比你两小时挣得还多
I make more in an hour than you make in two hours!
哦 演出要开始了
Oh, the play's about to start.
妈妈 这次的座位适合我的身材吗
Mom, am I going to fit in the seat
还是说会像上次一样杯具
or is this going to be like last time?
你应该会被卡在这里一段时间了
This should tide you over for a while.
我会尽快回来的
I'll come back as soon as I can.
她不会回来的
She's not coming back, you know.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为她也是我妈妈
'Cause she's my mom, too.
抱歉 这是我的座
Excuse me, that's my seat.
回家再跟你算账
We'll talk about this at home.
哎 看看谁会在这
Let's see who's in this thing?
杯具 路人
Sad. Nobody.
杯具 杯具 路人
Sad. Sad. Nobody.
Victor Garber?
百老汇著名演员
这个真心不错
That's pretty good.
他怎么请得到Victor...
How did he get Victor...?
哦 怪不得
Oh, of course.
今天来的是Randall Evan Battincourt
Tonight it's Randall Evan Battincourt.
我真讨厌这些替身演员
God, I hate understudies.
路易十六
King Louis the Sixteenth
被判上断头台处死
has been sentenced to death by guillotine.
路易十六这个角色
The part of King Louis the Sixteenth
将由Jean de Menard替演
will be played by Jean de Menard.
放轻松 你将完美地完成任务
Relax, you're going to do great.
搞定
Nailed it.
好了 和往常一样
Well, as usual,
这部剧一定会不讨好我们两个中的一个
this is gonna suck for one of us.
Donna 我是Grant 你的新婚丈夫
Donna? It's Grant, your new husband.
亲爱的
Hi, honey.
我有几个好消息
I've got great news.
是什么
What is it?
首先 我们把那瓶苏格兰威士忌佳酿放哪了
First, where do we keep the good scotch?
在你兄弟家里
At your brother's house.
我得到了一个在镇里最火的新话剧的试镜
I got an audition for the hottest new play in town.
这绝对能成就我的职业生涯
This could really make my career
然后我们就终于能开始过小日子了
and we can finally start our family.
那部剧叫什么
What's it called?
即兴爱人
A Passing Fancy.
这是这部剧的名字
That's the name of this play.
他怎么做到的 他怎么做到的
How did he do that? How did he do that?!
给 Donna
Here, Donna.
我给你买了结婚十周年的礼物
I got you your ten-year anniversary present.
防晒霜?
Suntan lotion?
但我们不是住在东北么
But we live in the Northeast.
的确 我们是住在东北
That's right, we do.
除非我们正要迁往加州
Unless we were moving to California.
他一定是已经拿到那里的角色了
He must've got the part.
阿根廷传奇第一夫人 她的生平被改编为音乐剧《阿根廷别为我哭泣》
他什么时候才会遇到贝隆夫人？
When he going to meet Evita?
不是每部剧都是贝隆夫人
Not every play is Evita.
哦 不 我觉得糟透了
Oh, no. I feel terrible.
为什么 你不想去吗
Why? Don't you want to go?
不想--我给你买了一件防风夹克
No-- I got you a parka.
这两个人永远都不合拍
Those two are never on the same page.
等着那个眼神...
Wait for the look...
这就是屡试不爽的原因
And that's why it works.
Donna 别走
Donna, don't go!
还不算太晚 我们还可以开始家庭生活
It's not too late. We can still start our family.
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
你已经有一个家庭了
You already have a family.
就在那儿
It's right there.
那可不能在夜里温暖你
Those won't keep you warm at night.
再见 Grant
Good-bye, Grant.
挺有意思 不是吗
It's funny, isn't it?
这么多年来 我就是即兴爱人
All these years, I was the passing fancy.
起立 混蛋
Get up, you jerk.
哇哦 棒极了
Wow, that was amazing!
我是说 通常 镇上的演出都烂透了
I mean, usually, the shows suck in this town.
比如Moishe 那个无精打采的犹太成人礼小丑
Like Moishe, the low-energy Bar Mitzvah clown.
哦 这是什么
Ooh, what's this?
一个两角五分硬币
A quarter.
我之前在你耳朵后面发现的
I found it behind your ear earlier.
好了 你已经看过够多的魔术了
All right, that's enough tricks for you.
我要去外套上躺会了
I'm going to go lie down on the coats.
嘿 谁看了演出的点评了吗
Hey, has anybody seen the review yet?
没有 我们都在等你
No, we've been waiting for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
哦 来了
Oh, here it is.
"真诚希望《即兴爱人》成为一段经久不衰的佳话
"Here's hoping A Passing Fancy is actually a staying fancy.
"最高的赞誉给编剧Brian Griffin
"The highest praise goes to playwright Brian Griffin
"为他在当代夫妻关系中
"for his hilarious and insightful look
"幽默和深刻的窥视
"into modern relationships.
"如果一个成年人只看一部剧
"If you see only one play as an adult,
我推荐你看这一部"
I urge you to see this one."
嘿 你能读一下那页
Hey, can you read that page
都是关于死人的小段落吗
with all the little paragraphs about dead people?
那些超级逗
Those are hilarious.
太好了 Brian 你现在怎么想
This is amazing, Brian. How do you feel?
你走红了
You're a hit!
这真是...难以想象的好
It's... overwhelming.
这就是我一直想要的 你们知道吗
This is all I've ever wanted, you know?
大家赏识并尊重我的作品
For people to appreciate and respect my writing.
我想写一部剧
I want to write a play!
啊 你真可爱 Stewie.
Aw, that's cute, Stewie.
也许有一天
Maybe someday.
不 我是说真的要写一部剧
No, I'm going to write a play.
我会做很多事情
I can do lots of things.
我曾经是《大青蛙布偶秀》的人力资源主管
I was the human resources director for the Muppets.
Beaker先生 我很遗憾
Mr. Beaker, it is my unfortunate task
要通知你
to inform you that your services
不必再来本公司上班了
will no longer be required by this company.
如果你一定要知道
Well, if you must know,
是因为我们发现了大量的
it's because we've noticed large quantities
苯和麻黄素
of benzene, ephedrine
而且每天都有硫酸镁泻药在丢失
and everyday Epsom salt have gone missing.
别辩解了
Oh, please.
我们都知道这些是用来做
We both know those are the ingredients
冰毒的原料
used to make crystal meth.
我还一直在思考
And I've got a pretty good idea
你究竟把冰毒卖给谁
who you've been selling it to as well.
哦 嘿 Beaker
Oh, hey, uh, Beaker,
等你跟朋友谈完之后
when you're done talking to your friend,
我想要 呃 呃...
I want to, uh, eh...
我想和你谈谈那个东西
I want to talk to you about that thing.
嘿 你在做什么
Hey, what you doing?
我正要排练我的新剧
I was going to start rehearsing my new play.
想看看吗
Want to hear it?
哦 你真的写了一部小话剧
Oh, you actually wrote a little play.
哦 我真希望我可以看看
Aw, boy, I wish I could hang out,
只是最近真的是忙疯了
but it has just gotten so crazy.
真的 我知道了 行了吧
Really? I know, right?
我是说 我不是在抱怨
I mean, I'm not complaining, you know?
我只是...我希望我可以重回以前的日子
But I just... I want my old life back.
我是在开玩笑 的确
I'm just kidding, of course.
我真是太开心了
I'm so grateful, you know?
我是说 每场演出都爆满
I mean, every performance is sold out
于是他们又在周三加了一个下午场
and they just added a Wednesday matinee.
很不错
It's great.
是有一个东西因为这件事情
I mean, there's only one thing I'm not getting
让我很无奈
out of this experience.
是什么  睡眠
What's that? Sleep.
不 我真的是非常开心 真的
No, no, I'm so grateful, really.
只是我一直 我一直太忙了
It's just that I'm-I'm so busy all the time.
不过真的很好 都很棒
But it's great. It's all great.
好吧 你觉得你有时间读一下吗
Well, do you think you might have time to read it?
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
但是有耐心点 行不
But be patient, all right?
我这一周排满了面试和出席活动
I've got interviews and appearances all week.
我是说 他们想要榨干
I mean, they're squeezing
我的所有时间和价值
every last drop they can out of me,
就像番茄酱一样
like a bottle of ketchup.
听着 我们已经折腾了15分钟
Listen, we've been at this for 15 minutes.
我不认为还有东西能出来
I don't think anything's coming out.
我还行 我还能等
I'm fine. I can keep going.
我只是太累了
I'm just really tired.
如果我把手指插到你的菊花里怎么样
What if I stick my finger in your hole?
想象一个画面 配上这些台词 自行脑补
呃 只有我快高潮的时候才有用
Eh, that only works when I'm already close.
美国话剧在走下坡路
The American play was dying.
我们-我们是否能让它在这里复苏
Have-have we brought it back to life here?
我不敢打包票 不过确实有起色了
I can't say that, but it has a pulse.
你真的是很牛叉的作家 Brian
You're such an amazing writer, Brian.
你怎么做到的  你写剧本的过程是怎样的
How do you do it? What's your process?
呃 Allison 我该怎么回答这个问题？
Oh, God, Allison, how do I even answer that?
我是说 彩虹诞生的过程是怎样的
Uh, I mean, what's a rainbow's process?
两分雨水 一分阳光 一分孩童的好奇
Two parts rain, one part sun, one part childlike wonder.
不过我们可以肯定的是
What we do know, though,
这两者最后带来的结果都是欢乐
is that the end result in both cases is joy.
哇哦
Wow.
哇哦 这下你觉得离开灯塔值了吧 Seamus
Wow, are you glad you left the lighthouse now, Seamus?
哦 至少我这么觉得 Seamus
Oh, I think so, Seamus!
打扰一下 我注意到您在高谈阔论
Excuse me, I noticed you were talking loud,
这么看来您是个智者
so that means you're smart.
您是否介意-我奢问一句-
But would you mind-- and I hate asking--
您介意为我签名吗
but would you mind signing this?
这个人让你觉得讨厌了吗 Brian
Is this guy giving you a hard time, Brian?
不 他没关系的
Nah, he's all right.
好的 行 行
All right. Cool, cool.
你怎么样 伙计
How you doing, buddy?
请过目 Stewie Griffin
美国婚姻
（莫扎特第29奏鸣曲）
天啊
My God.
太美妙了
It's miraculous.
靠
(bleep)
嘿 Brian 能读一下我写的剧本吗
Hey, Brian, can you read my play?
对不起 一个屁卡在剧本里了
Sorry, there was a fart trapped in the play.
嘿 Jasper 你好吗
Hey, Jasper, how are you?
嘿 Brian
Hey, Brian!
祝贺你的新剧大获成功
Congratulations on your new play.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thanks.
怎么了 你看起来状态不佳
What's wrong? You look awful.
发生什么了
What happened?
我读了Stewie写的剧本
I read the play Stewie wrote.
她现在写剧本
She writes plays now?
是的 而且那个剧本写得特别好
Yes, and it was brilliant.
Jasper 我这辈子都不可能再读到那样好的作品了
Jasper, I've never read anything like it in my life.
那个故事富有见解 新颖 而且很有灵气
It was insightful and fresh and intelligent.
就像他的剧本在嘲笑我
It's like his play is mocking me.
他一晚上写好的
He wrote it in a night.
呃 正如我在Bravo上看到Brad Goreski的感受一样
Ugh, that's how I feel whenever I see Brad Goreski on Bravo.
明星造型师 他在Bravo台推出了时尚节目"It's a Brad, Brad World"
天啊 除了我每个人都在Bravo上
God, everyone's on Bravo but me.
不过 你告诉他这剧本怎么样了么
Anyhoo, have you told him how good it is?
还没 我才刚读完
No. I just read it.
他给我剧本就是想要我的评价
He gave it to me 'cause he wanted my feedback.
好的 听我说
Okay, listen to me.
告诉Stewie剧本糟透了 是个垃圾
Tell Stewie it's awful, it's garbage.
要不择手段 Brian
Do whatever you have to do, Brian,
让他永远都不知道自己有天赋
but never let him know he's got talent.
没错 你说的对
Yeah, you're right.
这不会很难
It won't be so hard.
毕竟 我做过更过分的
After all, I've certainly done worse.
我把Peter的那罐"我不敢相信这竟然不是黄油"
I replaced Peter's I Can't Believe It's Not Butter
联合利华生产的一个牌子的人造黄油食品
换成了真的黄油
with real butter.
我...我不敢...我不敢相信...
I... I can't... I can't believe...
我不明白 医生
I don't know, Doctor.
回想一下 我觉得可能那是真的黄油
Looking back, I think it may have been real butter.
你丈夫谋杀了三个孩子
Your husband murdered three children.
哦 天啊 看看这个
Oh, my God. Look at this.
Brian 过来看看
Brian, get in here.
怎么了
What?
你的剧被提名为
Your play has been nominated
本地最具创造力事物的超级巨奖
for a local Hoggy Award for Best Creative Anything.
哦 太棒了
Oh, that's great.
呃 我要...
Um, I'm gonna...
我去呼吸点新鲜空气
I'm going to go get some air.
看看
Look at that.
被一个奖项提名
Nominated for an award.
你们两个今天做了什么
What have you two done today?
我在我的一个睾丸下面发现了一个肿块
I found a lump under one of my balls.
好吧 这的确是个发现
Okay, that's something.
我吃了四分之三的 Entenmann牌的点心
I ate three quarters of an Entenmann's strudel.
Entenmann出过苹果味的卷状点心 已停产
你们都是好孩子
Youse are good kids.
你有没有抽空读我的剧本呢
Hey, so did you get a chance to read my play?
呃...我读了
Uh... I did.
我读了
I did.
哦 我好紧张
Ooh, I'm so nervous.
你觉得怎样
What'd you think?
Stewie 我们是朋友 对吧
Stewie, you and I are friends, right?
嗯 我是说 我认识你
Yeah, I mean, I know you
是通过我们共同的朋友Greg
through our mutual friend Greg,
不过当然 我觉得我们现在是朋友了
but sure, I'd say we're friends now.
是啊 既然-既然是你的朋友
Exactly. And-and as your friend,
你希望我诚实地回答你 是吧
you'd want me to be honest with you, right?
当然
Totally.
剧本不咋样
It wasn't good.
哦 不 真的
Oh, no, really?
我写得如此用心
Oh, I worked so hard on it.
哦 我认为这个不错来着 唉
Oh, I thought it was good. Aw.
哦 我懂 我也衷心希望剧本不错来着
Oh, I know, I wanted it to be good so much.
哦 我太郁闷了
Oh, I am so bummed out right now.
我-我...我都不知道我是不是应该交稿了
I-I... Now I don't even know if I should submit it.
什么...交稿?
Wha... Submit it?
是的 我准备把它投递给
Yeah, I was planning to submit it
纽约隆德宝剧院公司
Roundabout Theatre Company in New York.
最著名的百老汇非盈利剧院公司之一
别！我是说...
No! I mean...
哦 我是说 这-这是一个不好的点子
Oh, I mean, that-that would be a bad idea.
绝对不好
Definitely not.
别 别 他们不会像我对你这么客气的
No, no, they won't let you down easy like I did.
纽约是非常严苛的 尤其对于外地人
New York can be pretty harsh, especially to outsiders.
嗨 纽约！
Hello, New York!
呃 也许你是对的 我会考虑的
Ugh, maybe you're right. I'll think about it.
不过 我能拿回来我的剧本吗?这是我唯一的一份
Anyway, can I have that back? It's my only copy.
你只有一份?
Your only copy?
是的
Yes.
还有谢谢你是这么好的一个朋友
And thank you for being a good friend
并且告诉我真相 Brian
and telling me the truth, Brian.
我知道这对你来说很难
I know that was hard for you.
为了表达我对你阅稿的感激之情
And to show my appreciation for reading my play,
我为你做了这个
I made you this.
官方认证 好狗
哇哦 "好狗"
Wow, "good dog."
并且是官方认证的?
And it's official?
就写在那 不是吗
That's what it says, doesn't it?
真希望我爸能活着看到这一幕
I wish my dad was alive to see this.
嘿
Hey.
你他娘是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是Stewie花钱雇来看着他睡觉的
I'm the guy Stewie pays to watch him sleep.
你又是谁
Who are you?
我是Brian 我住这
I'm Brian. I live here.
哦
Oh.
你介意我取走这个剧本吗
Do you mind if I take this script?
不介意 当然 随便
Yeah, sure, whatever.
他只让我看他睡觉
He just pays me to watch him sleep
并且同时用刀摩擦我的脸
and rub this knife across my face while I do it.
哦
Oh.
好吧
Okay.
嘿 stewie他付你多少钱
Hey, how much does Stewie pay you?
$4,800一周
$4,800 a week.
靠！
(bleep)
没错
Yeah.
嘿 Brian
Hey, Brian.
哦 嘿 Stewie
Oh, hey, Stewie.
听着 你看见我的剧本了么
Listen, have you seen my play?
哦 Stewie 我的确看了你的剧本
You know, Stewie, I have seen your play,
并且它让我愉悦
and it is exhilarating to me.
一个儿童的剧本是这个世界上
A child's play is one of
最美丽的东西之一
the most beautiful things in the world.
继续 小家伙
Continue to play, little one.
你是我们的未来
You're our future.
你他娘的在说什么
What the (bleep) are you talking about?
我写的剧本 你看见没
The play I wrote. Have you seen it?
呃 我不知道 我问问我的律师
Uh, I don't know. Let me call my lawyer.
嗨 我正在被盘问
(chuckles) Hello. I'm being cross-examined.
不 我没有...我没有看见你的剧本
No, I haven't... I haven't seen it.
真的?因为我就把它放在我的桌子上...
Really? 'Cause I had it sitting right on my table...
我说了我没有看见 行了吧！
I said I haven't seen it, all right!
而且 又怎么样呢?反正写的糟透了
And what does it matter? It was terrible anyway!
我们已经讨论过了
We've had this conversation!
你自己行行好 换个兴趣吧
Do yourself a favor and move on!
很有趣 Brian 因为我发现了这个
Well, that's interesting, Brian, because I found this
就埋在后院里你藏的骨头旁边
buried in the backyard next to your soup bone.
Stewie 我...
Stewie, I...
你想要摧毁它 不是吗
You tried to destroy it, didn't you?
我就知道我的剧本很好
I knew my play was good.
正如我知道你的剧本只是一个平庸的拼凑物
Just like I knew your play was a mediocre patchwork
充满老旧的观点和乏味的陈腔滥调
of hackneyed ideas and tired clichés.
你根本不知道有多难
You have no idea how hard it was
和那些粗里粗气的土鳖们一起坐在剧院里
to sit in that theater with all those braying hyenas.
难不成你能举出例证说明
Couldn't you tell something was up
Chris和那个死胖子跟得上剧情?
when Chris and the fat man could follow the plot?
我是说 Peter花了一年才明白精灵鼠小弟
I mean, it took Peter a year to figure out Stuart Little.
我突然明白了
I just figured it out.
"精灵"是指"老鼠"的意思
"Stuart" means "mouse."
不是的 Peter
No, Peter.
"小"指"老鼠"？
"Little" means "mouse"?
不是 Peter
No, Peter.
我感觉自己又落伍又迟钝
I feel so old and in the way.
那它还是一部不错的剧
It's still a good play!
它充斥着糟糕的下流双关语
It's filled with terrible double entendres,
俏皮话和偷来的点子
puns and stolen bits.
有一行都出自《宋飞传》
There's a line in there from Seinfeld!
NBC播出的著名情景喜剧(1989-1998)
我从没看过那个电视剧
I never saw that episode!
我有自己的心声
I have a voice.
你明白吗
Do you understand that?
一个作家需要心声 我就有
A writer needs a voice, and I have one.
你没有
You don't.
你的剧只迎合最低级趣味的共鸣 Brian
Your play panders to the lowest common denominator, Brian.
并且做的也并不够好
And it doesn't even do that well.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
愿每一个
May every person
嘲笑你菜鸟级"力作"的人
that laughs at your sophomoric effort
都提醒你记着自己永远的平庸
be a reminder of your eternal mediocrity
像尖刀一样刺穿你的心脏
and pierce your heart like a knife.
过来 混蛋
Come here, you bastard!
你让人讨厌
You stink!
你的剧本也让人讨厌
And your play stinks!
这跟我没关吧
This ain't about me, is it?
不
No.
我很抱歉...
And I'm sorry...
但是不能有人知道这个
but nobody can ever know that.
Donna 是Grant 你的新婚丈夫
Donna? It's Grant, your new husband!
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
我有几个好消息
I've got great news.
是什么
What is it?
首先 我们把那瓶苏格兰威士忌佳酿放哪了
First, where do we keep the good scotch?
在你兄弟家里
At your brother's house.
Lois 我能在这开我的生日聚会吗
PETER: Lois, can I have my birthday here?
看起来进行得不错
Seems to be going well.
你究竟想要什么
What do you want?
想分享一个好消息不
Wanted to share a bit of good news.
我刚才得知我的剧
I just found out that my play
将要在百老汇演出了
is going to be produced on Broadway.
什么
What?
并且我要带走Randall Evan Battincourt去演
And I'm taking Randall Evan Battincourt with me.
嗨 Stewie 我会过去的
Hi, Stewie. I'll be right there.
只是需要演完这个烂剧
I just got to finish this crap.
嘿 我需要你带我去纽约
Hey, I need you to take me to New York
参加我话剧的首映礼
for the opening night of my play.
没门
No way.
此外 我查过了 纽约没有任何
Besides, I checked, and there's no play
署名是Stewie Griffin的剧要上演
by Stewie Griffin opening in New York.
我是用假名交的稿
I submitted it under a pseudonym.
他们以为是Tony Dovolani写的
They think it was written by Tony Dovolani.
阿尔巴尼亚籍芭蕾舞演员 事业在纽约 是美国版的"与明星共舞"嘉宾
我以为你的假名是美艳的淫荡喷火器
I thought your pseudonym was Gorgeous Randy Flamethrower.
那是我的避嫌假名
That's my dodge ball pseudonym.
听着 如果你不愿意载我
Look, if you won't take me,
我能保证纽约剧院联盟会派个车来
I'm sure the New York Theater League would send a car.
纽约剧院联盟?为啥?
New York Theater League? Why?
因为他们为我举行了一个欢迎晚宴
Because they're throwing a welcome dinner in my honor.
真的?
Really?
我想 我可以改变一下我的行程
Well, I guess I could clear my schedule.
哦 你不会后悔的 Brian.
Oh, you won't regret it, Brian.
百老汇所有的重要人物都将出席
All the most important Broadway people will be there.
编剧 投资人 甚至是Stanley Kowalski
Playwrights, money men, even Stanley Kowalski.
百老汇音乐剧《欲望号列车》中的虚构人物
嗨 我是Michael
Hi. I'm Michael.
Michael!
呃 这是我妻子 Nancy
Um, and this is my wife, Nancy.
Nancy!
这是我们乌兹别克斯坦朋友 Bokyavroychesku
And this is our Uzbekistani friend, Bokyavroychesku.
嗨
Hi.
Stewie 你不觉得你穿这身夸张了吗
Stewie, don't you think you're overdoing it with that outfit.
脱下来时不能耍酷的衣服 我是不会穿的
I don't wear anything I can't take off with a flourish.
哇哦 这真是棒极了
Wow, this is amazing.
每个出名的编剧都在这
Every major playwright is here.
是的 看起来真是一个成功宴会
Yes, and it seems to be quite a successful party.
他们中有一些已经自杀了
Several of them have already committed suicide.
超赞的宴会
Great party.
毫无疑问
Totally!
嘿 Tony
MAN:Hey, Tony.
哦 上帝 是David Mamet
Oh, my God, that's David Mamet.
编剧 作家 导演 得过普利策 提名过Tony奖
今晚的明星来了
There's the man of the evening.
我读了你的剧本 美国婚姻
I read your play, An American Marriage.
不可思议般浑然天成 我可是相当地震撼啊
It was incredibly raw. I was pretty damn impressed.
哦 谢谢你 David
Oh, thank you, David.
David 这是Brian Brian David
David, this is Brian. Brian, David.
哦 我的荣幸
Oh, it's an honor.
我只是想对你说
Listen, I just want to say
《拜金一族》给我带来了多大的灵感
what an inspiration Glengarry Glen Ross was to me
百老汇戏剧 反映销售员业绩至上的生活 后搬上银幕
当我写自己的剧本的时候
when I was writing my own play.
别激动
Easy.
是Tony Dovolani吗
Is that Tony Dovolani?
嗨 Alan Bennett
Hello. Alan Bennett.
英格兰最受欢迎的编剧之一 也是作家 演员
绝佳的剧
Fantastic play.
我是Yasmina Reza
And I'm Yasmina Reza.
法国编剧 演员 小说家
哦 你是他的夜间护理吗
Oh, are you his night nurse?
不 我是个编剧
No, I'm a playwright.
我写过《艺术》以及《杀戮之神》
I wrote Art and God of Carnage.
我得过一个普利策奖
I won a Pulitzer.
你是不是还要告诉我们你的本科绩点?
You want to say your grade point average, too?
哇 这样齐聚一堂还真是诡异呢
Boy, it's just so weird to be in a room
屋里的每一个人都是编剧
where every single person in the room is a playwright.
我们中的每一个
Every single one of us.
每一个
Everyone.
包括我
Including me.
我是个编剧
I'm a playwright.
Brian 天啊 低调一下行不
Brian, my God, take it down a notch.
你也是编剧 在纽约吗?
You're a playwright? In New York?
在圆蛤市 罗德岛
Well, Quahog, Rhode Island.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
我们刚在罗德岛圆蛤市看了一出戏
We just went and saw a play in Quahog, Rhode Island.
真的?
Really?
你听说过《即兴爱人》没有?
Have you ever heard of A Passing Fancy?
听说过
I have!
哦 天啊 多大一坨垃圾啊
Oh, my God, what a load of rubbish.
如果要评出我们去过的
We have this thing where we go
能找到的最差地方剧院
to the worst regional theater we can find
并且让我们笑岔气
and laugh ourselves sick.
这个一定能拿大奖
And this one took the grand prize.
真的?
Really?
我-我听到的都是正面评价
I-I had heard only good things.
这真是一块XX他妈的在XX上
It was a (bleep) piece of (bleep) on a (bleep)!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
我听到David Mamet亲自骂人了
I got to hear David Mamet curse in person.
哦 你在这啊
Oh, there you are.
这是我这辈子经历过的最糟糕的晚上
That was the worst night of my life.
你并不是那里面唯一的死胖子
It's not like you were the only fat guy in there.
啥?
What?
哦 你是因为那部剧 抱歉
Oh, this is about the play. Sorry.
读到你的剧本之前我一直很高兴 Stewie
I was so happy until I read your play, Stewie.
我终于作为一个作家取得了点成功
I finally had some kind of success as a writer.
虽然并不大 但是我自己的
It wasn't big, but it was mine.
当个马马虎虎的作家我就知足了
I was fine being an okay writer,
直到我发现 自己和天才作家同在一个屋檐下
until I discovered I was living in a house with a brilliant one.
我知道我们不常讨论狗的寿命
I know we don't talk about doggy years a lot,
但是我-我就是希望你可以等到
but I-I just wish you could have waited
我死之后再来发掘自己的才华
to find out how talented you were until I was gone.
我死的时候 你甚至还不到10岁
By the time I'm dead, you won't even be ten.
你还有70年的生涯来伟大
You'll have 70 more years to be great.
我只希望自己可以享有五年的辉煌
I just wish I could have had five to be good.
这才是你的心声 Brian
There's your voice, Brian.
这是一个消沉的心声 但是你自己的
It's a depressing voice, but it's yours.
就从这里写起吧
Write from that.
听着 我和别的编剧
Listen, me and the other playwrights
准备出去
are going out to have drinks
和伍迪艾伦以及他的养女老婆喝几杯
with Woody Allen and his daughter-wife.
编剧导演 与前妻离婚并娶了10岁收养的养女 两人相差36岁
你要来吗
You want to come?
好吧
All right.
我们可以就在这坐一会儿
We can just sit here for a while.
你离开以后 他们说了更多关于你的难听话
They talked a lot more crap about you after you left.
美国婚姻 首映
哦天啊 真是糟透了 糟透了
Oh, God, that was just terrible. Terrible.
我不明白
I don't understand.
Stewie 你的剧本究竟发生了什么
Stewie, what happened to the play you wrote?
真是糟透了
That was terrible.
嗯 我最后又润色修改了一下
Well, I gave it a final polish..
改了几个地方
Changed a few things.
看来我最后还是把整件事搞砸了
Guess I kind of mucked the whole thing up.
但是怎么会?你...
But how? You...
等一下
Wait
你这么做是...为了我?
Did you do that... for me?
你在说什么?我是个年轻的编剧
What are you talking about? I'm a young writer.
我还没有像预想的那样准备好
I just wasn't as ready as I thought I was.
也许还需要几年 谁知道呢
Maybe in a couple of years, who knows?
Stewie 你不应该这么做的
Stewie, you shouldn't have done that.
不过...谢谢
But... thanks.
不谢 Brian
No problem, Brian.
嘿 咱俩现在回家怎么样?
Hey, what do you say we head back home?
听起来不错
That sounds good.
我准备再长大点就搬到纽约城来
You know, I'm going to move to New York City when I'm older,
因为这里灯火辉煌 大城市
'cause it's twinkly and big
并且这是个圆梦的地方
and this is where dreams come true,
那只大怪鸟冲我们飞过来了 是吗?
and that giant bird's coming for us, isn't he?